Guide to the Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers 1980-1987 MSS 249
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
Lisa Fox and Curt Royston Papers
1980-87
MSS 249
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
4.0 cubic feet
Fox, Lisa
Royston, Curt
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Arrangement
The collections is organized into five series based on format.
Series I: Paper and Photographs
Series II: Posters
Series III: Film
Series IV: Video
Series V: Audio
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Curt Royston Papers
Biographical Note
Curt Royston is best known for his proficiency in a variety of media: painting, sculpture, photography, film, and video, and often in combination. His work has been shown extensively throughout the United States and Europe including a 1987 one-man exhibition at the Whitney Museum of American Art. Lisa Fox was a leading dancer with the Merce Cunningham Dance Company from 1976-1980 and has been a choreographer with Lisa Fox Danse for over thirty years. Together Royston and Fox collaborated on a series of multimedia installations, as well as a number of 16mm dance-based films throughout the 1980s, the most popular of which is "In Artificial Light" (1983).
Scope and Content
This collection contains reviews, photographs, transparencies, posters, video and film related to the multimedia collaborations of Lisa Fox and Curt Royston.
Fox, Lisa; Royston, Curt
- Series I: Paper and Photographs
  - "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reviews, 1987-88 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [Transparencies, High Noon], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Posters
  - Lisa Fox, Danse, Salle Simon I. Patino, Cite Universitaire de Geneve, February 8, [19--] (Map-case 4.E)
  - The Kitchen USA Touring, June 14-15, [19--] (Map-case 4.E)
- Series III: Film
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access Copies may not be available for all material. Please consult a Fales Archivist.
    - In Artificial Light, a film by Curt Royston (2010 Restoration Print), 1982 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0094)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Gauge: 16mm
      Color, Sound
      TRT: 20 minutes
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Hothouse (title on print), undated (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0001)
      Length: 400 ft
    - Hothouse, 1985 (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0002)
    - Hothouse - 2nd Answer Print, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0003)
    - In Artificial Light, undated (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0004)
      Length:700 ft
    - In Artificial Light - Mag Track, undated (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0005)
    - Puss and Boots, c.a. 1980 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0006)
      Length:100 ft
    - Kitchen Show on the Staten Island Ferry, c.a. 1981 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0007)
    - Notes for an Adagio, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0008)
      Length:260 ft
    - Notes for an Adagio - Pix, c.a. 1982 (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0009)
    - White Shirt Place - Reel 1 - Mag Track, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0010)
      Length:850 ft
    - White Shirt Place - Reel 2 - Mag Track, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0011)
      Length:650 ft
    - In Artificial Light, undated (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0012)
      Length:670 ft
    - Hot House, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0013)
      Length:450 ft
    - En Passant, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 249.0014)
      Length:500 ft
    - Notes for an Adagio, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 249.0015)
      Length:140 ft
- Series IV: Video
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    - "High Noon In Half Light", undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0041)
      Format: DVD
      TRT: 00:35:00
      Source: ID: 249.0041
    - "High Noon In Half Light" / "Eye Light" Camera #1, 11/10/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0044)
      TRT: 00:32:00
      Source: ID: 249.0020
    - "High Noon In Half Light" / "All Our Hands" Camera #1, 11/10/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0047)
      TRT: 00:33:00
      Source: ID: 249.0021
    - Half Light - "Eye Light" Camera #2, 11/17/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0050)
      TRT: 00:25:00
      Source: ID: 249.0022
      General note
      Alternate Title: High Noon In Half Light
    - Half Light - "All Our Hands" Camera #2, 11/17/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0053)
      TRT: 00:10:00
      Source: ID: 249.0023
    - Half Light - "Blue Room" Camera #2, 11/17/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0056)
      TRT: 00:17:00
      Source: ID: 249.0024
    - "Eye Light" Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0059)
      TRT: 00:27:0025
      Source: ID: 249.0025
    - "All Our Hands" Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0062)
      TRT: 00:10:20
      Source: ID: 249.0026
    - "Blue Room" Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0065)
      TRT: 00:18:05
      Source: ID: 249.0027
    - Overhead Camera, Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0068)
      TRT: 00:03:00
      Source: ID: 249.0028
    - "In Artificial Light", 1983 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0071)
      TRT: 00:21:00
      Source: ID: 249.0029
    - "In Artificial Light" (2010 Restoration), 1983 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0097)
      Source: ID: 249.0094 - Telecine of 16mm print
    - Downtown Madonna, Part 2 + "In Artificial Light", undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0074)
      TRT: 00:34:00
      Source: ID: 249.0031
    - "Hot House", undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0077)
      TRT: 00:13:00
      Source: ID: 249.0033
    - "Hot House" Original Film to Video Transfer, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0080)
      TRT: 00:14:00
      Source: ID: 249.0034
    - "The Feast", January 1983 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0083)
      TRT: 00:08:00
      Source: ID: 249.0036
    - Lisa Fox & Rhys Chatham, Institute of Contemporary Art, January 1983 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 249.0086)
      TRT: 00:40:00
      Source: ID: 249.0037
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0016)
      Format: 1in
    - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0017)
    - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0018)
      Format: 3/4in Umatic
    - "High Noon in Half Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0019)
      Format: VHS
    - High Noon in Half Light: "Eye Light" Camera #1, 11/10/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0020)
      TRT: [unknown]
      Alternate Title: "High Noon in Half Light"
    - Half Light "All Our Hands" Camera #1, 11/10/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0021)
    - Half Light - "Eye Light" Camera #2, 11/17/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0022)
    - Half Light - "All Our Hands" Camera #2, 11/17/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0023)
    - Half Light - "Blue Room" Camera #2, 11/17/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0024)
    - "Eye Light" Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0025)
    - "All Our Hands" Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Box [1], Media ID: 249.0026)
    - "Blue Room" Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0027)
    - Overhead Cam Performance #3, 11/28/87 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0028)
    - "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0029)
      TRT: 00:19:41
    - "In Artificial Light", January 1983 (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0030)
      TRT: 00:20:00
    - Downtown Madonna Part 2 and "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0031)
      Format: Betacam SP
    - "In Artificial Light", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0032)
    - "Hot House", undated (Box 4, Media ID: 249.0033)
    - "Hot House" - Original film to video transfer, undated (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0034)
    - Lisa Fox "Floored", Kitchen Performance 12/10/81 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0035)
    - Lisa Fox "The Feast", January 1983 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0036)
    - "Lisa Fox & Rhys Chatham, Institute of Contemporary Art", January 1983 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0037)
    - [Untitled - Curt Royston], undated (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0038)
- Series V: Audio
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Hot House Rough Takes, June 1985 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0087)
      Alternate Title: Piano Takes with Harold - 6/85
    - June Mix, 6/2/82 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0088)
    - The Bunt, The Hunt, Floored - Swiss Mix, Feb 1982, February 1982 (Box 5, Media ID: 249.0089)